<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>

<?Fm Condition DITA-Topicmeta Red NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH hide?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Data AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "DITA-Comment"OR"DITA-Data"OR"DITA-Prolog" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id137JG0W00HS"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Requirements</title>
<shortdesc>Assumptions and requirements for effective use of FM2DITA.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2013-07-19"/>
<revised modified = "2013-08-04"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p><indexterm>requirements</indexterm><indexterm>assumptions</indexterm>FM2DITA
is a plugin that provides commands and utilities that assist with
the process of converting unstructured FrameMaker documents into
DITA. It is not a magic bullet that does everything for you (if
that’s what you’re looking for, hire a consultant). If used properly,
it will allow you to establish a reliable and consistent conversion
process and will save you a significant amount of time.</p>
<p>The following list describes the additional tools (both software
and mental) that will likely be required to make effective use of
this plugin.</p>
<ul><li><p><i>FrameMaker.</i> Version 7.2 or later.</p></li>
<li><p><i>DITA support in FrameMaker.</i> We recommend that you
use DITA-FMx to provide DITA support in FrameMaker (all versions),
but you can use this plugin with the default DITA support as well.</p></li>
<li><p><i>Conversion table development expertise.</i> This plugin
assumes that you have developed a conversion table that does the
initial conversion from unstructured FM files to structured FM files.
FM2DITA does provide “preconversion” tools and utilities that you may
want to use before applying the conversion table, but it does not
create the conversion table for you. If you do not have conversion
table development expertise, you can have this created for you by
a consultant, and you’ll be able to use this plugin to perform the
remainder of the conversion yourself.</p></li>
<li><p><i>DITA Open Toolkit or other validation tools.</i> After
completing the conversion process and breaking the structured FM
files into DITA topics and maps, it is often useful to have a command
line tool that you can run to do a quick sanity check validation
on the resulting files. This is not required, but will help to find
any problems that might become evident later.</p></li></ul></body></topic>
